A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Publications FA767
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation publications, 1936-2010; 1
  - Seminar on the Development and organization of Vocational Training and Technical Education (VTTE), 1965 (Box 30, Folder 332)
    "Twenty-four specialists in the administration and teaching of technical education from countries of the Middle East and Africa participated in a seminar on the Development and organization of Vocational Training and Technical Education, held at Horsholm High School, Denmark, August 30-October 16, 1965".
  - Understanding Population, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 333)
  - Violence Against Women: Addressing a Global Problem, 1992 March (Box 30, Folder 334)
  - Barriers: A New Look at the Needs of Young Adolescents, Joan Lipsitz, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 335)
  - Forty Years: A Learning Curve: the Ford Foundation's Programs in India, 1952-1992, Eugene S. Staples (Box 31, Folder 336)
  - The New Delhi Seminar on Media, Government, and the Law: A Ford Foundation Report, edited by Anne Lapping, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 337)
    Seminar: August 24-27, 1978.
  - Ford Foundation Grantmakers Orientation Handbook, 2006 (Box 31, Folder 338)
  - Social Science Research on Population and Development, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 339)
    Papers presented at a conference at the Ford Foundation, New York City, October 29-30, 1974.
  - Responding to the 9/11 Terrorist Attacks: Lessons from Relief and Recovery in New York City: A Report prepared for the Ford Foundation, by Tom Seessel, 2003 May (Box 31, Folder 340)
  - Ford Foundation - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program - Advancing Achievement and Understanding, 2003 (Box 31, Folder 341)
  - Minority Access to College: A Ford Foundation Report, Fred E. Crossland, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 342)
  - Not Working: Unskilled Youth and Displaced Adults, 1983 August (Box 31, Folder 343)
    A working paper from the Ford Foundation. "A look at the demographic, technical, and educational causes of youth and adult unemployment and at some program responses of the Ford Foundation".
  - New Approaches to Conflict Resolution: A Ford Foundation Report, 1978 May (Box 31, Folder 344)
  - International Collaboration in the Arts: A Report on the Ford Foundation Initiative, "Internationalizing New Work in the Performing Arts", Phase I: 1995-1998, by Douglas DeNatale and Karen L. Ito, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 345)
  - Matters of Choice: A Ford Foundation Report on Alternative Schools, 1974 September (Box 31, Folder 346)
  - National Women of Color Organizations: A Report to the Ford Foundation, Aileen C. Hernandez, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 347)
  - Minorities in the Media: A Ford Foundation Report, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 348)
  - Minorities in Business, Ford Foundation Assistance, 1965-1975 (Box 32, Folder 349)
  - Minority Contractor Bonding Program: A Manual of Organizational Steps and Procedures (Box 32, Folder 350)
  - Minority Admissions and Performance in Graduate Study, Rodney Hartnett and Benjamin F. Payton, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 351)
    "A Preliminary study of the fellowship programs of the Ford Foundation and the Danforth Foundation".
  - Minorities and Housing: Are the Doors Really Open?, by Robert Chandler, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 352)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint.
  - Minorities and Mathematics: A Ford Foundation Report, 1981 August (Box 32, Folder 353)
  - The Near Side of Federalism: Improving State and Local Government, 1972 January (Box 32, Folder 354)
  - New Options in the Philanthropic Process: A Ford Foundation Statement of Policy, 1968 November (Box 32, Folder 355)
  - A More Effective Arm: A Report on a Police Development Fund [Police Foundation], Newly Established by the Ford Foundation, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 356)
  - Mediating Social Conflict: A Ford Foundation Report, 1978 October (Box 32, Folder 357)
  - Pay-As-You-Earn: Ford Foundation Studies in Income Contingent Loans for Higher Education: Summary Report and Recommendations, 1972 September (Box 32, Folder 358)
  - Paying for Schools and Colleges: A Ford Foundation Report, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 359)
  - Handbook for Overseas [Ford Foundation] Staff, 1967 January (Box 32, Folder 360)
  - The Local Initiatives Support Corporation (LISC): A Private-Public Venture for Community and Neighborhood Revitalization, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 361)
  - Public Interest Law: Five Years Later, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 362)
  - Sexuality and Sexual Rights, Global Narratives and Conversations, Peru, 2007 June (Box 32, Folder 363)
  - Building Bridges: Community Development Corporations and the World of Employment Training, 1995 January (Box 32, Folder 364)
  - Sharps and Flats: A Report on Ford Foundation Assistance to American Music, 1980 July (Box 32, Folder 365)
  - The Search for a New Economic Order: A Ford Foundation Report, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 366)
  - Building Assets to Reduce Poverty and Injustice, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 367)
  - Ford Foundation Grants to Indian Organizations: Administrative Guidelines, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 368)
  - The Ford Foundation in India: Celebrating Fifty Years of Partnership and Looking Ahead: A Compendium of Fiftieth Anniversary Celebratory Grants, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 369)
  - The Ford Foundation [India] Regional Events Calendar, 2002-2003 (Box 32, Folder 370)
  - The Ford Foundation - India, Nepal, Sri Lanka: Statement of Current Interests, 1992-2003 (Box 32, Folder 371)
  - The Ford Foundation, New Delhi, India Field Office, Statement of Current Interests, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 372)
  - Asset Building for Social Change: Pathways to Large-Scale Impact, 2005 (Box 32, Folder 373)
  - Global Dialogues for Sexual Health and Well-Being: An Evaluation Report, by Peter Aggleton and Kate Wood, 2009 June (Box 32, Folder 374)
  - Rethinking Stabilization: Strengthening Arts Organizations During Times of Change, by Jane Culbert, William Keens, Laura Lewis Mandeles, Thomas Wolf, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 375)
    Based on a report prepared by Strategic Grantmaker Srvices for the Ford Foundation.
  - Seizing Opportunities: The Role of CDCs in Urban Economic Development, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 376)
  - Perspectives on India's Development in the 1990s: Papers, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 377)
    A Symposium: 28-29 January 1992, Nehru Memorial Library, New Delhi, India
  - Peace and Social Justice, Ford Foundation [program brochure], 2005 (Box 33, Folder 378)
  - The Ford Foundation: Brazil (Fundacao Ford: Brasil), 2005 (Box 33, Folder 379)
  - Ford Foundation: Office for the Andean Region and Southern Cone, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 380)
  - Law: Ford Foundation Grantees and the Pursuit of Justice, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 381)
  - Why We Can't Wait: A Case for Philanthropic Action: Opportunities for Improving Life Outcomes for African-American Males: A Report Prepared for the Ford Foundation, by Marcus J. Littles, Ryan Bowers, and Micah Gilmer, 2008 (Box 33, Folder 382)
  - The Ford Foundation in Brazil (A Fundacao ford no Brasil), 1998-1999 (Box 33, Folder 383)
  - Ford Foundation International Fellowships Program - Report, 2003-2004 (Box 33, Folder 384)
  - Advocacy for Reproductive Health and Women's Empowerment in India: A Ford Foundation Report, 1997 July (Box 33, Folder 385)
  - Part of the Solution: Leveraging Business and Markets for Low-Income People: Lessons Learned from the Ford Foundation Corporate Involvement Initiative (Box 33, Folder 386)
  - The Ford Foundation: Cairo [Egypt Field Office] (Box 33, Folder 387)
  - Momentum: Sustaining Efforts to Improve Life Outcomes Among African-American Males: A Report prepared for the Ford Foundation by Micah Gilmer, Marcus Littles and Ryan Bowers, 2008 December (Box 33, Folder 388)
  - The Ford Foundation in Southern Africa, 1999-2000 (Box 33, Folder 389)
  - Skills, Scholarship, and the Public Service, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 390)
  - The Society of the Streets, 1962 (Box 33, Folder 391)
  - Language Doors, 1964 May (Box 33, Folder 392)
  - Sexuality and Social Change: Making the Connection: Strategies for Action and Investment, 2005 (Box 33, Folder 393)
  - The Problem of Women and Mathematics: A Report to the Ford Foundation, Lynn H. Fox, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 394)
  - Program-Related Investments [PRIs]: A Different Approach to Philanthropy, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 395)
  - Student Aid and the urban Poor, by the Washington Office of the College Board, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 396)
    Ford Foundation Seires on Higher Education in the Cities.
  - A Tale of Three Cities: Boston, Birmingham, Hartford, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 397)
  - Toward a More Perfect Union: Basic Skills, Poor Families, and our Economic Future, by Gordon Berlin and Andrew Sum, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 398)
    Ford Foundation Project on social Welfare and the American Future, Occasional Paper 3.
  - Solving the Math Problem: The Ford Foundation's Work on Reforming middle and Secondary School Mathematics, 1980-1998 (Box 34, Folder 399)
  - Works in Progress: A Status Report on the Neighborhood and Family Initiative, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 400)
  - Who Administers? Access to Leadership Positions in the Administration of Government, Frank Logue, New Haven, Connecticut, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 401)
    A Survey and Report for the Division of National Affairs of the Ford Foundation.
  - Too Little, Too Late: Services for Teenage Parents, 1982 (Box 34, Folder 402)
    A working paper from the Ford Foundation, by Elizabeth A. McGee. "An examination of some major programs now operating in the United States to serve teenage parents and their children, including a look at the range and quality of available services and candid comments by service providers".
  - Toward Greatness in higher Education: A First Report on the Ford Foundation Special Program in Education, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 403)
  - Feminism in the Mid-1970s: The Non-Establishment, the Establishment, and the Future: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Maren Lockwood Carden, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 404)
  - Tax Equalization: Procedures for New York Appointed Overseas [Ford Foundation] Staff who are Citizens or Residents, 1984 (Box 34, Folder 405)
  - Urbanization in Kenya: Urbanization Trends and Prospects by Luigi Laurenti, and Rural Development and urban Growth by John Gerhart, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 406)
    An International Urbanization Survey Report to the Ford Foundation.
  - Urbanization in Morocco, by Katherine Marshall Johnson, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 407)
  - Urbanization in Nigeria: A Planning Commentary, by Leslie Green and Vincent Milone, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 408)
  - Urbanization in Tropical Africa: A Demographic Introduction, by Colin Rosser, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 409)
  - Urbanization in Zambia, by Alan J.F. Simmance, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 410)
  - That 51% [Percent]? Plus [Ford Foundation Activities Related to Opportunities for Women], 1979 (Box 34, Folder 411)
  - That 51% [Percent]: Ford Foundation Activities Related to Opportunities for Women, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 412)
  - Teacher Development in Schools: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by the Academy for Educational Development, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 413)
  - Theater Reawakening: A Report on Ford Foundation Assistance to American Drama, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 414)
  - Women in Blue-Collar Jobs: A Ford Foundation Conference Report, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 415)
  - Women in American Politics: A [Ford Foundation] Symposium of the Women's Program Forum, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 416)
  - William Wallace McPeak: A Memorial Service [obituary], 1964 (Box 35, Folder 417)
  - Violent Delinquents: A Report to the Ford Foundation from the Vera Institute of Justice, by Paul A. Strasburg, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 418)
  - Widening the Mainstream of American Culture: A Ford Foundation Report on Ethnic Studies, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 419)
  - Studying the Presidency: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Hugh Heclo, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 420)
  - Teaching by Television: A Report from the Ford Foundation and the Fund for the Advancement of Education, 1959; 1961 (Box 35, Folder 421)
  - Sustainable Solutions: Building Assets for Empowerment and Sustainable Development, 2002 (Box 35, Folder 422)
  - Financial Support of Women's Programs in the 1970s: A Review of Private and Government Funding in the United States and Abroad: A Report to the Ford Foundation, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 423)
  - Experiences in Building Cross-Field Partnerships for Sexuality and Reproductive Health, Partnerships Committee, Reproductive Health Affinity Group, Ford Foundation, 2001 January (Box 35, Folder 424)
  - ETV [Educational Television]: A Ford Foundation Pictorial Report, 1961 March (Box 35, Folder 425)
  - Papers on Research about Learning: Exceptional Teaching for Exceptional Learning: A Report to the Ford Foundation, by Nicholas Hobbs and others, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 426)
  - The Ford Foundation and Foundation-Supported Activities in India: Summary of Grants from 1951 to 1969, 1970 (Box 35, Folder 427)
  - Ford Foundation Humanities and the Arts Program Support in the Musical Arts, 1966 February (Box 35, Folder 428)
  - Notes: Bulletin of the Research Program on Population and Development Policy, number 1-2 - Ford Foundation and Rockefeller Foundation, 1979 January-July (Box 35, Folder 429)
  - EDAG Forum: Environment and Development Affinity Group, volume 1, issue 2, 1999 (Box 35, Folder 430)
  - Reproductive Health Affinity Group: Building Human and Social Assets, 2001 February (Box 35, Folder 431)
  - Ford Foundation Grants in? [each U.S. state], 1964 (Box 36, Folder 432, 433)
    Series of small booklets detailing Ford Foundation grants made in each U.S. state.
  - Welfare and Values in America: A Review of Attitudes toward Welfare and Welfare Policies in the Light of American History and Culture, by William Lee Miller, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 434)
    Welfare Policy Project - The Institute of Policy Sciences and Public Affairs of Duke University and the Ford Foundation.
  - Microsimulation: A Technique for Measuring the Impact of Federal Income Assistance Programs, by Herman P. Miller and Roger A. Herroit, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 435)
  - Attitudes Toward Public Welfare Programs and Recipients in the United States: A Review of Public Opinion Surveys, 1935-1976, by Natalie Jaffe, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 436)
  - The Dynamics of Welfare Dependency: A Survey, by David W. Lyon, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 437)
  - Administration of Public Welfare in the Case of Aid to Families with Dependent Children, by Abe Lavine, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 438)
  - Whose Ox Would be Healed? The Financial Effects of Federalization of Welfare, by Edward K. Hamilton and Francine F. Rabinovitz, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 439)
  - Work and Welfare in the 1970s, by Sar A. Levitan, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 440)
  - Toward Income Opportunity: Current Thinking on Welfare Reform, by Lester M. Salamon, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 441)
  - Source Directory: Assistance to Third World Broadcasters, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 442)
    Ford Foundation/British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC)
  - The Ford Foundation in West Africa, 1980s (Box 37, Folder 443)
  - Ford Foundation International Fellowship Program: Policies and Standards, 1961 April (Box 37, Folder 444)
  - Ford Foundation World Wide Web Site pamphlet, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 445)
  - From Lower Class to Underclass: The Poor in American Social Science, 1930-1970, by Alice O'Connor, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 446, 447, 448)
    PhD Dissertation, Johns Hopkins University
  - Ford Foundation Travel and Study Grants / Individual Grants, 1971-1979 (Box 38, Folder 449)
    Includes lists of travel and study grant (after 1971, "Individual grants") recipients; arranged by program, then A-Z by grantee's name.
  - Report on the Proceedings of the Public Interest Law Conference, San Diego, California, 1974 April 15-17 (Box 38, Folder 450)
  - Native Arts and Cultures: Research, Growth and Opportunities for Philanthropic Support, 2010 (Box 38, Folder 451)
  - Ford Foundation Projects Listed by Program Areas, 1951 January-1952 September (Box 38, Folder 452)
  - Faculty Salaries, Hospital Support, Medical Education: A Statement by the Trustees of the Ford Foundation, Special Appropriations, 1955 December8-10 (Box 38, Folder 453)
  - Ford Foundation: Indonesia, 1970-2006 (Box 38, Folder 454)
    Jakarta, Indonesia field office pamphlets, booklets, brochures.
  - The Ford Foundation Program in Pakistan, 1964-1975 (Box 38, Folder 455)
    Pakistan field office pamphlets, booklets, brochures.
  - The Ford Foundation in India, 1951-1968 (Box 38, Folder 456)
  - The Ford Foundation in the 1960s: Statement of the Board of Trustees on Policies, Programs, and Operations, 1962 July (Box 38, Folder 457)
    Report of the Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s (also known as the "Slater Committee" or the "McCloy Review Committee" ).
  - Ford Foundation, Self Help, Fannie Mae - Affordable mortgages initiative press kit, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 458)
  - Seven Nations, Six Foundations, One Mission: Africa's Future - Partnership for Higher Education in Africa press kit, 2005 (Box 38, Folder 459)
  - The Ford Foundation and Educational Television, 1966 June (Box 38, Folder 460)
    Summary grants, and lists of grantees.
  - Women in the Arts: Current Debates, Future Directions - Martha Boesing, Laura Dean, Zelda Fichandler, Margaret Buford Wilkerson, 1989 (Box 38, Folder 461)
    "A dialogue with four distinguished performing artists and scholars". Transcript of a seminar held in March 1988 sponsored by the Ford Foundation's Women's Program Forum.
  - You and the Ford Foundation, 1959-1970s (Box 38, Folder 462)
  - Ford Foundation: Cairo, 2005 (Box 38, Folder 463)
    Cairo, Egypt field office brochure.
  - Cultivators of Change, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 464)
    "This report describes Ford Foundation assistance to selected activities in Syria, Lebanon, Jordan, Iraq, and Saudi Arabia'.
  - Cross Section, 1965 (Box 39, Folder 465)
  - Context the World, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 466)
  - ?And Justice for All, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 467)
  - Prospecting in Economics, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 468)
  - The Apprentice Experts, 1964 (Box 39, Folder 469)
  - Child Survival/Fair Start, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 470)
    "A look at the factors threatening the survival, health, and cognitive development of the world's disadvantaged children, and at the Ford Foundation's new program to help these children get a fair start in life". A working paper from the Ford Foundation.
  - Civil Rights, Social Justice, and Black America, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 471)
    "A review of past and current Ford Foundation efforts to promote racial justice for black Americans in employment, education, housing, political participation, and other areas". A working paper from the Ford Foundation.
  - American Community Development, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 472)
    "Preliminary Reports by Directors of Projects Assisted by the Ford Foundation in Four Cities and a State". Twenty-Ninth Annual National Conference, National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials, Denver, Colorado, October 1, 1963.
  - Changing Relations: Newcomers and Established Residents in U.S. Communities: A Report to the Ford Foundation by the National Board of the Changing Relations Project, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 473)
  - Crossing Borders: Revitalizing Area Studies, 1999 (Box 39, Folder 474)
  - Graduate Education and Black Americans, by Fred Crossland, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 475)
    Office of Special Projects, Division of Education and Research.
  - Financing an Effective United Nations: A Report of the Independent Advisory Group on U.N. Financing, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 476)
    "A Project of the Ford Foundation".
  - The Ford Foundation and the United Nations, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 477)
  - Ford Foundation Activities in Noncommercial Broadcasting, 1951-1976 (Box 39, Folder 478)
  - Ford Foundation Assistance to Native Americans, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 479)
  - Ford Foundation Assistance to Puerto Ricans, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 480)
  - Ford Foundation Experiments in Regional Environmental Management: A Symposium of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1974 (Box 39, Folder 481)
  - Careers in Teaching Engineering: A Report on the Ford Foundation Forgivable Loan Program, 1965 (Box 39, Folder 482)
  - The Ford Foundation, Buildings and Gardens, Lodi Estate, New Delhi, India, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 483)
    Photographic booklet describing the Ford Foundation's New Delhi Field Office's buildings, architecture, landscaping, and gardens.
  - The Ford Foundation and St. Louis, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 484)
  - Reproductive Health, Sexuality and Economic Development: Bridging the Divide, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 485)
    Reproductive Health Affinity Group Meeting, Istanbul, Turkey, May 15-21, 1998.
  - Ford Foundation Doctoral Fellowships for American Indian Students, 1972-1973 (Box 39, Folder 486)
  - The Ford Foundation Vietnam Program: A Resource for Innovations, 1999 June (Box 39, Folder 487)
    Vietnam program brochure.
  - A Decent Place to Live, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 488)
  - Early Childhood Services: A National Challenge, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 489)
  - A Richer Harvest, 1967 (Box 40, Folder 490)
    A Report on Ford Foundation Grants in Overseas Agriculture
  - Leadership Program for Community Foundations, Round III, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 491)
    The Ford Foundation and the John D. and Catherine T. Mac Arthur Foundation.
  - From Gatekeeper to Gateway: Transforming Testing in America, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 492)
    Report of the National Commission on Testing and Public Policy.
  - National Academic Achievement and Transfer Project, 1989 (Box 40, Folder 493)
    Public Response to a New Initiative of the American Council on Education and the Ford Foundation.
  - Innovations in State and Local Government news clippings, 1990 September-November (Box 40, Folder 494)
    An Awards Program of the Ford Foundation and the John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University.
  - Roundtable Justice: Case Studies in Conflict Resolution: Report s to the Ford Foundation, edited by Robert B. Goldmann, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 495)
    Westview Special Studies in Peace, Conflict, and Conflict Resolution.
  - Settling Thing: Six Case Studies in Environmental Mediation, by Allan R. Talbot, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 496)
    Published by the Conservation Foundation and the Ford Foundation.
  - Women's Leadership, Gender and Peace: Reflections on a Meeting at the Ford Foundation, by Sanam Naraghi-Anderlini, 2001 (Box 40, Folder 497)
  - Investing for Social Gain: Reflections on Two Decades of Program-Related Investments (PRIs), 1994 (Box 40, Folder 498)
  - Health Policy in the United States: Issues and Options, by Lawrence D. Brown, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 499)
    Ford Foundation Project on Social Welfare and the American Future, Occasional Paper 4.
  - Reproductive Health: A Strategy for the 1990s, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 500)
  - Worldwide Workshop on Youth Involvement as a Strategy for Social, Economic, and Democratic Development, 2000 (Box 40, Folder 501)
    Held in San Jose, Costa Rica, January 4-7, 2000.
  - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA), Ibadan, Nigeria, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 502)
    Promotional booklet.
  - A World in Need of Leadership: Tomorrow's United Nations, 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 503)
    A Study made possible by the Ford Foundation and the Dag Hammarskj"ld Foundation.
  - The Ford Foundation's 40 Years in Brazil: A Partnership for Social Change, by Nigel Brooke and Mary Witoshynsky, 2002 (Box 41, Folder 504)
  - Visual Voices: 100 Photographs of Village China by the Women of Yunnan Province, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 505)
  - A Selected Chronology of the Ford Foundation, 1936-1979 (Box 41, Folder 506)
  - The Ford Foundation Charter and Bylaws, 1980 September (Box 41, Folder 507)
  - Ford Foundation - Office of Communications Style Guide, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 508)
  - The Art of the Ford Foundation Building, by Andrew Carnduff Ritchie, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 509)